Elmer Gertz Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Legal File, 1905-1992 (Box 13-300)
  - Professional, 1905-1992 (Box 18-300)
    - Lome v. United Press Int'l
      - Correspondence, 1963-1965
      - Court documents, 1964, undated
    - Lonk v. Board of Educ.
      - Background information
        - 1943-1962
        - 1963-1964, undated, (2 folders) (Box 136)
      - Correspondence, 1961-1965, undated
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1963, undated
        - General, 1962-1963, undated
    - Lopes v. Thompson, 1976-1982, undated, (3 folders)
    - Louis L. Weinzelbaum, Inc. v. St Andrew's Church, 1956-1959, undated
    - Lowenthal & Gomper Supply Co. v. Fleetwood Realty Co., 1910, 1946-1975, undated, (4 folders)
    - Lunt-Lake Apartments Ass'n, Chicago, Ill. (Box 137)
      - Architects and engineers, 1946-1947, undated
      - Billing, 1947, undated
      - General
        - 1945-1947, (7 folders)
        - 1948-1949, undated, (3 folders) (Box 138)
      - Press, 1946-1947, undated
      - Zoning, 1945-1946, undated, (2 folders)
    - Madel v. Jefferson-19Leavell Publishing Co.
      - Background information, 1945-68, undated, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1944-1968, undated, (2 folders)
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1962
        - General, 1962-1968, undated, (8 folders) (Box 139)
    - Madjar v. Board of Trustees of Ill. Masonic Hosp.
      - Background information
        - General, 1958-1974, (2 folders)
        - Tax documents, 1966-1973, undated, (2 folders) (Box 140)
      - Correspondence, 1968-1974, undated, (2 folders)
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1972-1973, (4 folders)
        - General
          - 1971-1973, (2 folders)
          - 1974, undated (Box 141)
    - Magee v. Williams
      - Background information, 1947-1964, undated, (6 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1962-1964, undated, (2 folders)
      - Court documents
        - 1963, (2 folders)
        - 1964, undated, (5 folders) (Box 142)
    - Mandel v. Jordan, undated
    - Martin-Trigona, Anthony R., 1975-1978, undated
    - Maxwell v. Bishop
      - Background information, 1968-1969, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1968-1970
      - Court documents, 1968-1969, undated, (3 folders) (Box 143)
    - McCormick v. Green See Container 335, Restrictive covenants
    - McGautha v. California, 1970-1971
    - McManus, Lee C., 1964-1967, undated
    - McNeal v. Ogilvie, 1968, undated
    - Methadone Maintenance Inst. v. Newsweek, 1976-1977
    - Meyer, Russ
      - Beyond the Valley of the Dolls, 1969-1971, undated
      - Billing, 1969-1973, undated, (2 folders)
      - Cherry, Harry and Raquel (Box 144)
        - General, 1969-1970, undated
        - Georgia, 1969-1972, undated, (4 folders)
        - Iowa, 1970, undated
        - Ohio, 1970
        - Press, 1969-1970, undated
        - Texas, 1970, undated
        - Wisconsin, 1969
      - Citizens for Decent Literature, Cincinnati, Ohio
        - 1960-1970, (4 folders)
        - 1970-1972, undated, (2 folders) (Box 145)
      - Contract provisions, 1969
      - Film festivals, 1970-1971
      - Finders Keepers, Lovers Weepers, 1969-1971, (2 folders)
      - Gilbreth, Jack, 1969-1972
      - Press
        - Allied News Co., 1969
        - General, 1967-1972, undated, (3 folders)
      - Seven Minutes
        - General, 1970-1971, undated
        - Press, 1970-1971, undated, (2 folders)
        - Scripts (Box 146)
          - Changes, 1970, (4 folders)
          - General, 1970, (3 folders)
      - Vixen (Box 147)
        - Background information
          - General, 1968-1971, undated, (3 folders)
          - Grove Press v. Flask, 1969-1972, undated, (5 folders)
        - Canada, 1970
        - Film rental, 1971
        - Florida
          - By case
            - Cox v. Morsillo, 1969-1970
            - Florida v. Mandell, 1969 (Box 148)
            - Mandell v. Carson, 1969, undated For additional material see Container 148, Meyer v. Austin
            - Meyer v. Austin
              - Background information, 1969-1973, undated, (2 folders)
              - Correspondence
                - 1970-1974, undated, (3 folders)
              - Court documents
                - Depositions, 1969-1970, (3 folders)
                - General, 1969-1973, undated, (7 folders) (Box 149)
          - By jurisdiction
            - Gainesville, 1970, undated
            - Jacksonville
              - Correspondence
                - 1969
                - 1970-1971 (Box 150)
              - General, 1969-1970, undated, (2 folders)
            - Pinellas County, 1969, undated
        - General, 1969-1973, undated, (4 folders)
        - Georgia
          - 1968-1969, (2 folders)
          - 1969-1970, undated, (2 folders) (Box 151)
        - Illinois
          - By case
            - Eve Prods. v. Unger, 1969-1970
            - Illinois v. Butler
              - Correspondence, 1969-1972, (3 folders)
              - Court documents
                - 1969-1971, (3 folders)
                - Undated, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 152)
              - General, 1970, undated
            - Illinois v. Frisina Enters., 1970-1971, undated
          - Miscellaneous
            - Exhibits, 1968-1969, undated
            - Legal memoranda, undated
            - Notes, undated
        - Indiana, 1970-1973, undated, (2 folders)
        - Jury instructions, undated
        - Kentucky, 1971, undated
        - Louisiana, 1969-1970, undated
        - Massachusetts
          - Background information, 1969-1970, undated
          - Correspondence, 1969-1970
          - Court documents, 1969-1970, undated
        - Michigan
          - Background information, 1969, undated
          - Correspondence, 1969-1970, (2 folders) (Box 153)
          - Court documents, 1969, undated
        - Missouri
          - Background information, 1970, undated
          - Correspondence, 1970-1971, (3 folders)
          - Court documents, 1970-1971, undated, (3 folders)
        - New Hampshire, 1969-1970
        - New York, 1969
        - North Carolina, 1969
        - Ohio (Box 154)
          - By case
            - Eve Prods. v. City of Cincinnati
              - Background information, 1969-1971, undated, (2 folders)
              - Correspondence, 1969-1971, undated, (3 folders)
              - Court documents
                - 1969, (2 folders)
                - 1969-1971, undated, (8 folders) (Box 155)
              - Press, 1969-1970, undated
            - Ohio ex rel. Keating v. Vixen
              - Background information
                - 1967-1970
                - 1970-1972, undated, (2 folders) (Box 156)
              - Correspondence, 1969-1974, (8 folders)
              - Court documents (Box 157)
                - 1969, (6 folders) (Box 158)
                - 1970-1971, (6 folders) (Box 159)
                - 1971-1973, (3 folders) (Box 160)
                - Undated, (4 folders); (2 folders) (Box 161)
            - Ohio v. Malibu, Inc.
              - Background information, 1969-1971
              - Correspondence, 1969-1971
          - By jurisdiction
            - Cleveland, 1969-1971, undated
        - Playdates, 1969-1970, undated
        - Press, 1968-1971, undated, (3 folders)
        - Texas
          - Background information, 1969-1970, undated
          - Correspondence
            - 1969
            - 1970-1972, (2 folders) (Box 162)
          - Court documents, 1969-1971, undated, (5 folders)
          - Press, 1970-1971
        - Utah, 1970
        - Wisconsin
          - Milwaukee
            - Background information, 1968-1970, undated
            - Correspondence
              - 1969
              - 1970-1971 (Box 163)
            - Court documents, 1969-1970, undated, (4 folders)
            - Press, 1969
          - Oshkosh, 1969
          - Racine, 1968-1969, undated
    - Meyer v. Infant Welfare Soc'y
      - Background information, 1956-1970, undated, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1968-1970, undated, (3 folders)
    - Meyer v. Seamans, 1969-1974, undated, (3 folders) (Box 164)
    - Michelson v. Illinois Inst. of Technology, 1983, undated
    - Midwest Bank Builders v. Dun & Bradstreet
      - Correspondence, 1975-1978, undated
      - Court documents, 1975-1978, undated, (5 folders)
    - Miller v. State Bd. of Tax Comm'rs, 1975, undated (Box 165)
    - In re Milton
      - Background information, 1958-1962, undated
      - Correspondence, 1968
      - Court documents, 1968, undated
    - Minsky v. Stroden
      - Correspondence, 1966-1972
      - Court documents, 1966-1971, undated, (3 folders)
      - Fair Employment Practices Comm'n information, 1963-1966
      - General, 1951-1972, undated, (2 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1947, 1962-1988, undated, (2 folders)
    - Mohan v. Keer, 1970-1972
    - Moore v. Illinois (Box 166)
      - Background information, 1969-1971, undated, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1969-1973, undated
      - Court documents, 1968-1971, undated, (2 folders)
    - Morse, Richard L. D.
      - Background information, 1967, undated
      - Correspondence, 1967
    - Motorola v. Illinois Fair Employment Practices Comm'n
      - Background information
        - 1941-1966, (4 folders)
        - Undated, (3 folders) (Box 167)
      - Correspondence, 1964-1966, undated, (2 folders)
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1965
        - General
          - 1963-1965, (4 folders)
          - 1965-1967, undated, (4 folders) (Box 168)
    - Myers v. Rock Island Argus
      - Background information, 1971-1972, undated, (2 folders)
      - Billing, 1972-1973
      - Correspondence, 1972, undated
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1971
        - General, 1969-1971
    - Nash, Jay Robert, 1968-1970, 1976-1977, (2 folders)
    - National Insider, Inc. (Box 169)
      - Cases
        - Best Medium Publishing Co. v. National Insider
          - Background information
            - General
              - 1957-1966, (7 folders)
              - 1967-1968, undated, (4 folders) (Box 170)
            - Publishing rights, 1964-1965
            - Semple, Churchill, 1964
            - Singer, Kurt, 1964, undated
          - Correspondence
            - 1963-1964, (2 folders)
            - 1964-1968, undated, (7 folders) (Box 171)
          - Court documents
            - Exhibits
              - 1954-1967, (2 folders)
              - 1967, (8 folders) (Box 172)
              - 1967, undated (Box 173)
            - General
              - 1963-1968, (6 folders)
              - Undated, (7 folders) (Box 174)
            - Transcripts, 1964-1966, (4 folders) (Box 175)
        - Connecticut v. Four Issues of The National Insider (Box 176)
          - Background information, 1962-1965, undated, (3 folders)
          - Correspondence, 1964-1966, (6 folders)
          - Court documents, 1964-1966, undated, (5 folders) (Box 177)
          - Press, selected samples, 1964-1965
        - Connecticut v. Two Issues of The Keyhole
          - 1964, (3 folders)
          - 1965-1970, undated, (2 folders) (Box 178)
        - Illinois v. Goldfischer, 1965, (2 folders)
        - Illinois v. Rosen, 1965
        - Illinois v. Treiman, 1965
        - National Insider v. Chicago Transit Auth.
          - Background information, 1960-1967, undated
          - Correspondence, 1963-1967
          - Court documents, 1964, undated
        - National Insider v. Cowles Communications
          - 1962-1966, (3 folders)
          - 1967-1969 (Box 179)
        - National Insider v. Nangle, 1964-1965
        - National Insider v. Rolfes, 1963-1964
        - New York v. Mexican Divorce Assocs., 1964-1965, undated, (4 folders)
        - Texas v. Schabbehar, 1967
      - Miscellaneous
        - Billing, 1964-1965
        - Correspondence
          - 1963, (2 folders)
          - 1963-1964, (7 folders) (Box 180)
          - 1964-1966, (7 folders) (Box 181)
        - General
          - 1963-1964
          - 1964-1969, undated, (4 folders) (Box 182)
        - National Insider, selected samples, 1963-1969, (2 folders)
    - National Tattler, 1964-1965
    - Newman v. Congregation B'nai Shalom, 1959-1965, undated
    - Norgard v. United Airlines
      - 1961-1967, (2 folders)
      - 1968-1972, undated, (3 folders) (Box 183)
    - Norris, Hoke and Edna D., 1974-1978, undated, (2 folders)
    - North Carolina v. Waddell, 1973
    - North Central Airlines, 1968
    - Northrup v. Publishers Promotion Agency, 1964-1965, undated
    - Novak, Burton, 1971, undated
    - Novel v. Garrison
      - Background information
        - General
          - 1966-1968, (3 folders)
          - 1969-1972, undated, (6 folders) (Box 184)
        - Novel, Gordon M., financial papers
          - 1958-1961, (3 folders)
          - 1962-1966, undated, (9 folders) (Box 185)
        - Novel, Marlene, 1960-1964, undated
      - Billing, 1972, undated
      - Correspondence
        - 1965-1967
        - 1968-1972, undated, (7 folders) (Box 186)
      - Court documents
        - Depositions
          - 1969, (1 folder); (5 folders) (Box 187)
          - 1969-1970, (7 folders) (Box 188)
          - 1970 (Box 189)
        - Exhibits
          - 1967-1971, (6 folders)
          - Undated (Box 190)
        - General
          - 1967-1969, (6 folders)
          - 1969-1972, (6 folders) (Box 191)
          - Undated, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 192)
      - Press
        - General, 1967-1968
        - Scrapbook, 1967 See Oversize
    - Novel Books, Inc.
      - Friedman-Lewis contract, 1964, undated
      - The Men's Digest, 1963-1964
      - New Classics House, 1964-1965
      - Novel Books v. City of Chicago
        - Background information
          - 1957-1964, (4 folders)
          - Undated See also Oversize
        - Correspondence, 1964-1966, (2 folders) (Box 193)
        - Court documents
          - Exhibits, 1963, undated
          - General, 1964, undated
    - Obscenity cases See also names of individual cases
      - 1922-1969, (7 folders)
      - 1969-1972, (10 folders) (Box 194)
      - 1973-1975, undated, (7 folders) (Box 195)
    - Oh Calcutta
      - Illinois v. Waukegan Drive-In
        - Background information, 1931-1971, undated, (3 folders)
        - Billing, undated
        - Correspondence, 1970-1971, undated, (2 folders) (Box 196)
        - Court documents
          - Exhibits, 1970
          - General, 1970, undated
      - Kohlberg Theaters v. Calkins, 1970
    - Olson, Beatrice B.
      - Background information, 1946-1947, undated
      - Correspondence, 1946-1948, undated
    - Oppenheimer, Leo
      - Background information, 1964-1966, undated
      - Correspondence, 1964-1966, undated
    - Ormsby v. A. S. Barnes & Co., 1962-1969
    - Ornstein, Allan C., 1971-1973, undated
    - Osina v. Hebrew Theological College, 1968-1974, undated, (2 folders)
    - Palomar Pictures International, 1968-1969, undated
    - Pancotto v. Dun & Bradstreet (Box 197)
      - Background information, 1969-1971, undated, (2 folders)
      - Billing, 1971-1972
      - Correspondence, 1969-1971, undated, (3 folders)
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1969-1971
        - General
          - 1969-1970, (4 folders)
          - 1971, undated, (3 folders) (Box 198)
    - Parmelee v. Hearst Publishing Co.
      - Background information
        - 1913-1951, (5 folders)
        - Undated, (9 folders) (Box 199)
      - Correspondence, 1942-1961, undated, (7 folders) (Box 200)
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1943, undated
        - General
          - 1948-1950, (4 folders)
          - 1950-1954, undated, (5 folders) (Box 201)
    - Parmelee v. King Features Syndicate, 1948-1949
    - Parochelli, Mary Lynn, 1966-1968, undated
    - In re Perl
      - Background information, 1949-1964, undated, (3 folders)
      - Correspondence
        - 1960-1961
        - 1962-1964, undated, (2 folders) (Box 202)
      - Court documents, 1961-1963, undated, (5 folders)
    - Peter, George, 1969-1970, undated
    - Peters v. H. O. Reno Co.
      - Background information, 1949
      - Correspondence, 1949-1955
    - Pfendler v. Anshe Emet Day School
      - General
        - 1976-1977
        - 1978-1980, undated, (7 folders) (Box 203)
      - Newsletters, 1974-1976, undated, (2 folders)
    - In re Phillips, 1977 (Box 204)
    - Pohl v. Field Enters.
      - Background information
        - 1965-1967, (7 folders)
        - 1967, (5 folders) (Box 205)
      - Correspondence, 1967, undated
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1967
        - General, 1967
    - Polish-American Guardian Society, 1968
    - Posters by Post, 1970-1972
    - In re Powell, 1974
    - Pupillo v. DeCherrie, 1982-1983, undated
    - Purity Waters v. International Bhd. of Teamsters Locals 705, 744 & 738 (Box 206)
      - Correspondence, 1962, undated
      - Court documents, 1962-1964, undated
    - Raven, Seymour
      - Background information, 1966-1970, undated
      - Correspondence, 1963-1969, undated
    - In re Reed, 1955-1962, 1983
    - Rembar, Charles, 1964-1968, undated For additional material see Container 101, Illinois v. Romaine, (3 folders)
    - In re Ritholz
      - Background information, 1956-1958, undated, (4 folders)
      - Parole board documents, 1956-1957, undated (Box 207)
    - Rogers, Herbert J., 1968-1969
    - Rohrer v. Small, 1988-1989 See also Containers 55-57, Doe v. Small, (6 folders)
    - Rosee v. Board of Trade of the City of Chicago, 1965-1982, undated (Box 208)
    - Rosenberg v. Evans
      - Background information, 1924, 1943-1963, undated, (5 folders)
      - Correspondence
        - 1959-1961, (3 folders)
        - 1962-1963 (Box 209)
      - Court documents
        - 1959-1961, (6 folders)
        - 1962-1963, undated, (4 folders)
    - Rosenthal v. Illinois Inst. of Technology
      - 1963-1968
      - 1969-1975, undated, (9 folders) (Box 210)
    - In re Ross
      - 1974, (2 folders)
      - 1975, undated (Box 211)
    - Rottwin, Marcel and Anna, 1948-1949, undated
    - Rubin, Marvin R., 1972-1978, (2 folders)
    - Ruby, Jack
      - Alskog, Inc. and Capitol Records, re the assassination of John F. Kennedy
        - Correspondence, 1966-1967
        - General, 1966-1967, undated, (3 folders)
        - Press, 1967
      - Estate
        - Background information, 1967, undated
        - Correspondence
          - 1965-1967
          - 1967-1968 (Box 212)
        - Court documents, 1966-1967
        - Press, 1965-1967
      - Levin, Michael, documents, 1963-1965, (3 folders)
    - Ruby v. McDonald, undated
    - Ruby v. Saturday Evening Post, 1964-1966, undated
    - Ruby v. Texas For additional material see Containers 428-435, Moment of Madness
      - Background information
        - Appeal in the Court of Criminal Appeals of Texas
          - 1964-1967, (2 folders)
          - Undated, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 213)
        - Brown, Joseph B.
          - Book, undated, (2 folders)
          - Disqualification as judge, 1964-1966, (2 folders)
        - Dean, Patrick, 1967, undated, (3 folders)
        - General (Box 214)
          - 1958-1967, (8 folders)
          - Undated, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 215)
      - Interviews, 1963-1964
      - Notebooks
        - 1963-1965, (4 folders)
        - 1966-1967, undated, (2 folders) (Box 216)
      - Sanity hearing
        - 1963-1965, (2 folders)
        - 1966-1967, undated, (6 folders) (Box 217)
      - Transcripts
        - Change of venue hearing, 1964, (4 folders); (6 folders) (Box 218)
        - General, 1964, (3 folders); (6 folders); (7 folders) (Box 219, Box 220, Box 221)
        - Jury selection, 1964, (5 folders); (8 folders); (9 folders) (Box 222, Box 223, Box 224)
      - Warren Commission (Box 225)
        - Report and hearings
          - General, 1964, (7 folders); (6 folders) (Box 226)
          - Index, 1964
          - Press analysis
            - 1964, (2 folders)
            - 1965-1967, (4 folders) (Box 227)
        - Statements
          - Carroll, Marion, undated
          - Grant, Eva, 1964
          - Kaminsky, Eileen, 1964
          - Rubenstein, Hyman, 1964
          - Ruby, Earl, 1964
          - Ruby, Sam, undated
          - Volpert, Anne, undated
    - Correspondence (Box 228)
      - 1964-1965, (10 folders)
      - 1966, (9 folders) (Box 229)
      - 1967, undated, (2 folders) (Box 230)
    - Court documents
      - Exhibits, 1964-1965
      - General
        - 1965, (5 folders)
        - 1965-1966, (7 folders) (Box 231)
        - 1966-1967, undated, (7 folders) (Box 232)
      - Miscellany, 1964-1970, undated
      - Notes of Eva Grant and Paul Rothstein, undated
      - Press, 1963-1967, undated, (7 folders) (Box 233)
    - Scheidelman v. Hazdra
      - Correspondence, 1966-1969, undated, (2 folders)
      - Court documents, 1968, undated
    - Schnackenberg, Paul, 1976-1978 (Box 234)
    - Serrins v. Kane
      - Background information, 1965-1966, undated
      - Correspondence, 1965-1967, undated
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1966, undated
        - General, undated
    - Shaw v. Garrison
      - Background information, 1963-1971, undated, (5 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1968-1972
      - Court documents, 1968-1972, (4 folders)
    - Shure, Arnold I., 1973-1974 (Box 235)
    - Shutterbug Publishing Co.
      - Background information, 1959-1960, undated, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1960, undated
    - Silverman, Alan J., 1970
    - Silverman v. Board of Trustees
      - Background information
        - 1970-1971, (7 folders)
        - 1972-1973, undated, (7 folders) (Box 236)
      - Billing, 1972-1973
      - Correspondence
        - 1952-1971, (3 folders)
        - 1971-1979, undated, (11 folders) (Box 237)
      - Court documents (Box 238)
        - Exhibits, 1971, (7 folders)
        - General
          - 1972-1973, (3 folders)
          - 1973, undated, (4 folders) (Box 239)
    - Simon v. Besselman, 1968-1971
    - Simons v. Roach
      - Background information, 1948-1966, undated
      - Correspondence, 1966-1968, undated
      - Court documents, 1966-1967, undated
    - Slaw, Irving, 1947-1948
    - Small v. Kusper
      - 1986-1987, (2 folders)
      - 1987, undated (Box 240)
    - Smith, Ronald C.
      - Background information, 1971-1972, undated
      - Correspondence, 1971-1972, undated
    - Solomon v. Tribune Co.
      - Background information, undated
      - Correspondence, 1962-1965, undated
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1963
        - General, 1962-1964, undated
    - Sparkle-Crete Co.
      - Background information, 1949-1950, undated
      - Correspondence, 1949-1950, undated, (3 folders)
    - Sparks v. North Carolina, 1974-1975
    - Speck v. Illinois
      - Background information
        - 1966-1967
        - 1968-1971, undated, (2 folders) (Box 241)
      - Correspondence, 1967-1971
      - Court documents, 1967-1972, (4 folders)
    - Spielman, Henry
      - Background information, 1927-1963
      - Correspondence, 1963-1966, undated, (5 folders) (Box 242)
      - Court documents, 1964-1966, undated, (2 folders)
    - Staff
      - Giampietro, Wayne B.
        - 1963-1968, (4 folders)
        - 1969-1972, (10 folders) (Box 243)
        - 1972-1982, undated, (11 folders) (Box 244)
      - Seidman, Elizabeth Hubbard, 1975
    - Stamm, Orville (Box 245)
      - General, 1918-1967, undated, (7 folders)
      - Null, Samuel, 1957-1960, undated
      - Stamm-O-Lite, Inc., 1939-1954, undated
    - Starrett, Vincent, 1970-1986
    - Stewart, William S., 1960-1961, undated (Box 246)
    - Strauss v. Smith
      - Background information, 1943-1972, undated, (6 folders)
      - Billing, 1972
      - Correspondence, 1962-1972, undated, (5 folders)
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1967, undated
        - General, 1968-1971, undated, (3 folders) (Box 247)
    - Stuck v. Salvato See also Container 75, Freiwald v. Salvato, 1969-1972